http://www.britishshowhorse.org/privacy-policy.asp

Events Calendar
Qualifiers (Show Map)
Events Calendar
Qualifiers (Show Map)
Telephone    01462 437770
British Show Horse AssociationGeneral Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)Privacy Notice1.        Introduction1.1.     The British Show Horse Association (BSHA) is committed to protecting your personal information and respecting your privacy.1.2.     This Privacy Notice sets out the basis on which any personal data that we collect from or about you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.1.3.     For the purpose of the General Data Protection Regulation [the GDPR], the data controller is The British Show Horse Association.1.4.     We may update this Privacy Notice from time to time. Please check back regularly to see any updates or changes to this Notice.2.        Data Protection Contact2.1.      The contact details for the Secretary for any data protection queries are as follows:             2.1.1.     Email: admin@britishshowhorse.org             2.1.2.     Tel:     01462 437770 (10:00am to 04:00pm)3.        Data Protection Principles3.1.     We will comply with data protection law. This says that the personal information we hold about you must be:             3.1.1.     Used lawfully, fairly and in a transparent way             3.1.2.     Collected only for valid purposes that we have clearly explained to you and not used in any way that is incompatible with those purposes             3.1.3.     Relevant to the purposes we have told you about and limited only to those purposes             3.1.4.      Accurate and kept up to date             3.1.5.     Kept only as long as necessary for the purposes we have told you about             3.1.6.     Kept securely4.        Particulars of processing4.1.     We process personal data about Members, Judges, Ring Stewards and Competitors/Exhibitors at BSHA events. The categories of person about whom we process personal data are               described in more detail in the Annex to this Privacy Notice.5.         Your rights as a data subject5.1.      The General Data Protection Regulation provides the following rights (subject to some exemptions):             5.1.1.     The right to request access to the personal data that we hold about you             5.1.2.     The right to request rectification of the personal data that we hold about you             5.1.3.     The right to request erasure of the personal data that we hold about you             5.1.4.     The right to request restriction of processing about you             5.1.5.     The right to object to processing; and             5.1.6.     The right to data portability             If you wish to raise a complaint on how the BSHA has handled your personal data, you can contact the Secretary at the details above.             If you are not satisfied with the response or believe we are processing your personal data not in accordance with the law, you can complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office              (ICO) full contact details for which can be found at https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/6.          How we will use information about you6.1.       We will only use your personal information when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal information in the following circumstances:             6.1.1.     Where we need to perform the contract, you have entered into with us             6.1.2.     Where we need to comply with a legal obligation             6.1.3.     Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests6.2.       We may also use your personal information in the following situations, which are likely to be rare:             6.2.1.     Where we need to protect your interests (or someone else's interests)             6.2.2.     Where it is needed in the public interest (or for official purposes)6.3.      We will generally process your personal data for contractual necessity in providing membership services and events. We may also use personal information for additional relevant and             related purposes where you might reasonably expect us to do so, where the benefits of doing so are not outweighed by your own interests or fundamental rights or freedoms. This may             include:             6.3.1.     To maintain the records and other administrative purposes, including updating your details and preferences             6.3.2.     To assist with queries, complaints and dispute resolution             6.3.3.     For communications related to membership and invitations to participate in equine market research or equine health studies             6.3.4.     To assist with upholding the Association’s constitution and taking action in cases where there may be a breach of the Association’s Rules6.4.       We will ask for your direct consent IF we intend to use your personal data for marketing purposes. Where the processing of personal data is based on your having given consent, you             have the right, as a data subject, to withdraw that consent at any time. If you wish to invoke this right, please notify the Secretary using the contact details set out in Section 2 above.6.5.       You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority. In the United Kingdom, the supervisory authority is the Office of the Information Commissioner, full contact details             for which can be found at https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/7.          Recipients of Data7.1.       We may use service providers to help us provide you with our services. Personal data may be transferred to such service provider, who act for, or on our behalf, for further processing in             accordance with the purpose(s) for which the data was originally collected or may otherwise be lawfully processed.7.2.       Such third parties have contracted with us as data processors under the requirements in the GDPR. They are contractually bound to only use personal data for the agreed purpose(s).             Relevant persons working for these third parties will have access to your personal data under the terms of the data processor contract, but only to the extent necessary to perform their              services for us.7.3.       These data processors agree to implement reasonable contractual and technical protections, to keep your data confidential, not to sell your personal data to third parties and to not             disclose your personal data to third parties except as may be required by law, as permitted by us or as stated in this Privacy Policy.7.4.       In appropriate circumstances we may disclose data to authorised bodies as required by law.8.           Visitors to the British Show Horse Association website – Cookie Policy8.1.        About cookies:               8.1.1.     A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent                              back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server               8.1.2.     Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted                              by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is close               8.1.3.     Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in                             and obtained from cookies.8.2.         We use cookies to monitor how people use the BSHA website and for the following reasons:               8.2.1.     authentication - we use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website. Cookies used for this purpose are: Names available upon                              request                     8.2.2.     status - we use cookies to help us to determine if you are logged into our website. Cookies used for this purpose are: Names available upon request               8.2.3.     personalisation - we use cookies to store information about your preferences and to personalise the website for you. Cookies used for this purpose are: 'sitesecurebasket'               8.2.4.     security - we use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our                              website and services generally. Names available upon request               8.2.5.     advertising - we do not use cookies to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you               8.2.6.     analysis - we use Google cookies to help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and services. Cookies used for this purpose are specified by Google               8.2.7.     cookie consent - we use cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more generally. Cookies used for this purpose are: Names available upon request8.3.         We collect these cookies under Legitimate Interests in order to provide you with our online services and to analyse visitor behaviour on our website.8.4.         Cookie information is held on your browser and you can amend your browser settings at any time. However, please be aware that blocking or deleting all cookies will affect the usability                of the BSHA website.8.5.         Please see our Cookie Policy for further information on data we collect through our websites and how you can block and delete cookies: for a copy of the cookie policy please click here8.6.         Cookies used by our service providers               8.6.1.     Our service providers use cookies and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website               8.6.2.     We use Google Analytics to analyse the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to                              our website is used to create reports about the use of our website. Google's privacy policy is available at: www.google.com/policies/privacy                8.6.3.     We do not publish Google AdSense interest-based advertisements on our website               8.6.4.     Our cookie policy and usage is here9.            Publicity and Intellectual Property9.1.          Competitions may be recorded and videos, photographs and other recordings may be taken where an Entrant may be captured participating in the Competition. The Entrant agrees to                the publication of such photographs, videos, recordings and/or likenesses of the Entrant (whether edited, adapted, modified or copied) and their use by the Organiser and those                authorised by the Organiser, without prior notice or compensation, in any way which the Organiser may see fit now or in the future including but not limited to film, broadcast, radio,                TV, publications, future events and publicity. The Entrant acknowledges that the Organiser has the full right to sell and/or profit from the commercial use of such photographs, motion                 pictures, recordings and/or likenesses of the Entrant.9.2.          Any audio, visual or audio-visual recordings that are made by (or on behalf of) the Entrant of the Competition or any part of it are for personal use and cannot be published or used for                any commercial purpose without the prior written consent of the Organiser.9.3.          The Entrant accepts and agrees that, if they win, the Organiser may announce their names, age and town of residence on the Organiser’s website(s) and may use the same for publicity                 purposes which may include sharing and/or using the Entrant’s details with the press and the Organiser’s PR advisers.9.4.          The Entrant agrees and acknowledges that nothing in these Rules grants the Entrant any rights in or to any intellectual property owned or controlled by the Organiser.10.           Contact details10.1         Please contact the General Secretary if you have any questions or concerns about personal data and privacy matters.10.2         Our office is at:                 Office Suite 16                 Intech House                 34-35 The Cam Centre                 Wilbury Way                 Hitchin                 Herts                 SG4 0TW                 United Kingdom10.3.        Our principal place of business is at:                Office Suite 16                Intech House                34-35 The Cam Centre                Wilbury Way                Hitchin                Herts                SG4 0TW                United Kingdom10.4.        You can contact us:                10.4.1.     by post, to the postal address given above                10.4.2.     using our website contact form                10.4.3.     by telephone, on +44 (0)1462 437770 (10:am to 04:00pm) or                10.4.4.     by email, using the email address published on our websiteANNEXThis Annex sets out the British Show Horse Association’s processing of personal data relating to Members (including Board Members), Judges and Competitors/Exhibitors at BSHA and BSHA Affiliated events.What personal data do we process, why do we process it and what is the lawful basis? Members[List of personal data processed e.g.:]NameAddressEmail addressTelephone number/sDate of BirthWe process your personal data for the following purposes:         [Purpose]                                                                                                                                                                                                          [Lawful basis]Provision of membership services including administration and transactional communications relating to membership            Contractual NecessityUpholding the Association’s Rules and Code of Ethics                                                                                                                            Contractual NecessityCompliance with Horse of the Year Show Rules and Regulations                                                                                                          Contractual NecessityContacting you regarding newsletters, invitations and information about Association events/meetings                                           Legitimate InterestsPublication in the Association’s Newsletters or on the Association’s website                                                                                                   ConsentContacting you by email to provide related information and information/marketing communications (if any)                                            ConsentJudges[List of personal data processed e.g.:]NameAddressEmailaddressTelephone number/sDate of BirthWe process your personal data for the following purposes:          [Purpose]                                                                                                                                                                                                                 [Lawful basis]Administration and transactional communications relating to judging appointments                                                                              Contractual NecessityUpholding the Association’s Rules and Code of Ethics                                                                                                                                  Contractual NecessityCompliance with Horse of the Year Show Rules and Regulations (including sharing relevant required information)                            Contractual NecessityPublication in the Association’s Judges’ list and for appointments in the Show/Event Show Dates Lists, Schedules, Catalogues          Legitimate InterestsExhibitors/Competitors[List of personal data processed e.g.:]NameAddressEmailaddressTelephone number/sDate of BirthHorse informationWe process your personal data for the following purposes:          [Purpose]                                                                                                                                                                                              [Lawful basis]Administration and transactional communications for exhibitors/competitors entering BSHA events                             Contractual NecessityProvision of services relating to BSHA events                                                                                                                           Contractual NecessityUpholding the Association’s Rules and Code of Ethics                                                                                                             Contractual NecessityCompliance with the Horse of the Year Show Rules and Regulations                                                                                    Contractual NecessityContacting you regarding future events                                                                                                                                      Legitimate InterestsPublication of your name address and horse information in show/event catalogue (subject to the right to object)         Legitimate InterestsPublication of event results on the BSHA websites or any other relevant publications                                                         Legitimate InterestsWe also process personal data for the Association’s legitimate interests as we have outlined in the main Privacy Notice. Please be assured that we will always take account of your personal data rights in doing so.Where do we obtain your personal data from?Most of the above personal data is received direct from you (the data subject). However, information may be received from third parties (e.g. Producer, Family Member, Friend, Owner).How long do we hold your personal data for?Personal data will be retained indefinitely as required by the Association for the legitimate interests of the sport for the purpose of historical records.Are you obliged to provide us with your personal data?You are not obliged to provide the personal data in question. However, if you do not provide the personal data, we will be unable to perform any contract you have entered into with the British Show Horse Association for the provision of membership services, judging appointments or event services.Recipients of your personal dataWe disclose data to the following outsourced data processors in line with the main Privacy Policy, for the purposes of:Affiliated Show (Judges Only) for the purpose of selecting and inviting JudgesRSCC – for the backup of the Associations dataDragon Printers – for the printing of the Association’s Rule Book, Show CatalogueThe Deadline - for the printing of the Show Catalogue, NewsletterMedia Creative Ltd. – for the purpose data transfer to the websiteTo Associations/Societies for the purpose of checking entries and the results of affiliated classes at BSHA Shows/EventsWorld Pay for the processing of debit/credit card paymentsDo we use your data for any automated decision-making?No personal data is processed for automated decision-makingAny financial data arising from a transactional process will be held securely by the British Show Horse Association in accordance and compliance with all statutory and HMRC requirements.
